My name is Mr Williams. I am from Akwa Ibom. I am 61 years old.
I have a BA in Music and Masters in Public Order.
I was a Principal Master, Grade 2 in a secondary school. I taught music.
I am here to make a confession.
I am a retired teacher.
While in the service, before I retired, I engaged myself in 419.
That is, I was a fake native doctor.
We worked in groups. My target was always a retired governor or top politician.
I would go to him and discuss with him.
I would ask him, "Why can't you go and contest an election?"
He would say, "Ah, I don't have money oo. The last time I went, I lost a lot of money".
I would tell him, "Don't worry, I will take you to a friend who is going to sponsor your election".
I would now take him to a friend of mine who was also a fake witch doctor.
When we got to the man, the man would...
You mean, sir, you would take him to a friend who is claiming,
pretending to be a witch doctor - a native doctor.
A native doctor but also a fake one.
When we got there, the man would ask him to pay a consultation fee of about 10 000.
He would pay. Then the man would look at the mirror and say, "Ok, you are going to win the election.
How much do you do want?" The man would say, "I need about 500 million".
He would say, "That is a small money".
He would tell him what he had to buy so that we would release the money to him.
When he bought those things and brought them, we would sacrifice them.
After sometime, the fake native doctor would tell the man
that he would have to pay 10% of the amount of money before he could carry it.
The man would calculate 10% of the 500 million and say, "I don't have up to that.
I have about 10 million in the house or 2 million".
He would say, "Ok, go and bring it". He would go and bring the money.
The native doctor had a pot where we burnt this money.
Inside that pot, there was a hole.
As soon as the man put that million in that pot, the money would just go down.
Then he would use ordinary paper to put on top.
There was a pipe connected inside the pot.
The fake native doctor would know how to put the money so that it would be on the pipe.
It would not be on the pot. Then we would use paper and grass, and light them.
The papers and the grasses would be burning.
The person would be thinking that that money was burning,
not knowing that there was a pipe inside.
After some time I would go back to the man; we would share the money.
After that, when the man came back again, we would enter the shrine.
The fake native doctor would ask him to bring the remaining money before he could carry the money.
He would say that he didn't have up to that.
He would then say, "Ok, go and bring whatsoever you have".
He would go and bring another money but it would not be up to the 10%.
We burnt the other money too. Then after that, we entered the shrine.
The native doctor would now ask him, "Since you don't have the money, go and bring a livestock -
bonga fish" - you know this fish, as soon as you bring it from the water, it will die.
So it is not easy to bring it to the man.
The man would think that it was a very simple something.
He would go to the riverside and ask for bonga fish. They would give it to him.
As soon as he got to the doctor, the fish would die.
He would ask him to go again. The man would repeat up to 5 or 6 times.
Then later on he would say, "Ok, since you cannot bring it,
go and find money and complete the amount so that you can carry the 500 million".
The man would go back again to look for money to come and give.
If he brought another money, we could change it and say, "Go and look for a white cat".
You know it's very impossible to find a pure white cat.
The man would go all over Nigeria looking for a cat without seeing it.
When the man was tired of it, he would not come; he would go away.
And that's how you would have collected huge amounts of money from that man.
Yes. That was how we collected the money from that man without the man knowing.
And at the end of the day, you never actually gave the money that he was asking for - the 500 million.
It would never be given to the man. You would have extorted, collected huge amounts.
He would never get the 500 million since he had not fulfilled the ritual.
After some time, these things started to worry me because I had made so many people cry.
I decided that I would come and make a confession.
Apart from that, as a civil servant, your colleague knows your basic or annual salary.
I was having millions. I was buying cars, building a house with this bad money.
So I decided to put Emmanuel TV in my house.
Sorry, sir. Before going ahead, we just want to understand as well.
Are you saying that your colleagues in the school where you were working were suspecting you
because the money you were having was a lot more than the salary you were earning as a teacher?
Yes, they were suspecting me because the money I had was more than my basic salary.
So to cover up, I established an Emmanuel TV fellowship centre in my place.
The people would be thinking that I was blessed because I used to come to Lagos.
When I came to Lagos, I would get the Morning Water.
Upon getting back home, I would give it to them free.
They would be thinking that I was blessed by Prophet T.B. Joshua,
not knowing that I was doing another thing.
Ok. I hope we are understanding what our father is saying.
That because of the amount of money he had obtained dubiously, in a deceptive manner,
people were suspecting him. So to cover this up, he actually established a centre
whereby people would come to watch Emmanuel TV in his house
so that people who came and saw the riches he had would attribute it to the fact
that he used to come to The SCOAN, visited Prophet T.B. Joshua, received the Morning Water,
not knowing that actually the source of the money that he had was these dubious activities
he was engaging in, pretending to be a witch doctor and deceiving people through that means.
So you mean to say, sir, that many people were coming to your house to watch Emmanuel TV,
not knowing that behind the scenes, you were involved in this 419.
Yes. Many would come because they love Emmanuel TV; they would come and watch it.
I even published it in a paper that it was free, that people should come and watch it.
I have never used the name of the church to dupe any person.
So you mean to say, sir, you published it in a local newspaper
that they should come to your house and watch Emmanuel TV.
Yes.
Ok. So we are listening to our father giving this confession right now.
Now, sir, what was the reason that you actually decided finally to come down
to the church today and give this confession?
After I had stopped this 419 business for over 2 years,
I discovered that my son who is about 12 years started stealing.
I know that the spirit has transferred from me to him.
So I had to come to The SCOAN to confess.
And we want to understand, sir: All of the riches, the money you gained
through these deceitful practices, what did you end up using them for?
I made millions; on some days, I made up to 10 million but all this money -
if you ask me, I don't know where the money is now.
All the money is gone.
So you mean that you didn't use it for any good purpose?
I didn't use it for any good thing.
And right now as you are talking, the spirit that was in you, pushing you to these activities,
your son has now started stealing. And what are the kind of activities your son is doing?
My son started stealing in the school - he is in nursery school.
He would be deceiving people, "Give me 1000, tomorrow I will bring you 20 000".
And he would be collecting money from the small small boys.
So I actually know that the spirit has left me and entered him.
So now you are here in The SCOAN, sir, what do you want to say?
I want to ask for forgiveness.
I am a sinner. I have made so many people cry.
I ask God to forgive me my sins.
People of God, we have listened to the confession of our father here.
Before we hear a last word from him, there are some important and valuable lessons
that we are learning from his experience. Remember that Prophet T.B. Joshua says:
Whatever satan gives you with his right hand that would seem to give you apparent peace
or money or joy, he will take from you with his left hand what your life depends on.
Because anything that starts dubiously will surely end dubiously.
There is an important lesson for us to learn.
We know there are many people - some maybe watching today
some may even be here in the church - who are still in that same type of business
and you feel that you are prospering on the outside,
you feel you have riches, you feel you have wealth, cars, properties
but what you are doing, the end result will lead to destruction.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua says: We should value processing more than results
because if the way and manner we go about things is not according to God's way,
the end results will be bad.
And you can see our father here - he is an educated man - as an elderly man,
at the time he is supposed to be enjoying the fruits of his labour,
he is facing this crisis. His own son is afflicted with this spirit.
The money that he made through these dubious practices has disappeared.
And he has come back to the house of God to give this type of confession.
What is your advice to people around the world, especially those watching now
who may still be involved in such activities?
My advice to the people all over the world and people watching me here:
Don't look for power and don't be greedy.
Once you look for power or you are greedy, you are open for people to dupe you.
Ok, sir, that is clearly an advice for those who are seeking things from other sources, outside of God.
People going to witch doctors, herbalists, thinking that they will be able to provide a solution.
But they are also many people like yourself who are actually deceiving individuals,
claiming to be what they are not and deceiving them.
For such people, what is your advice to them?
People who are still doing the same business I was doing, I would advice you to stay away from it.
It is not a good thing.
You make millions but at the end of the day, you don't see 1 kobo,
if you are lucky to escape from jail.
Standard For Life
My name is Mr Williams.
This is my first daughter Martha, 25 years,
my second daughter Ruth, 23 years,
my third daughter Abigail, 22 years,
my fourth daughter Esther, 21 years,
my fifth daughter Rebecca, 17 years,
my last daughter Sarah, 16 years, and my grandchild,
my first son Godswill,
my second son Aaron,
my nephew Nefreke Williams.
Mr Williams & Family
Akwa Ibom, Nigeria
Ok, sir, you mean to say you are here with your 8 biological children and your nephew
and you have come back to The SCOAN with all your children.
Yes. I am here with my family. My six daughters, two boys and my nephew.
Sir, when you gave a confession here in The SCOAN last week,
you mentioned that one of your sons was having a particular problem.
Can just tell us who that son is and what the problem was he was having.
Ok, my first son Godswill was having a spiritual attack.
He used to steal. Now the problem is over; he has been delivered.
So you mean to say, sir, that after you gave your confession here at The SCOAN,
you subsequently brought your entire family,
including your young son who was afflicted with that spirit of stealing
so that they too can receive prayer and deliverance to start a new life.
Yes. Prophet T.B. Joshua gave me the transport money
to bring them from the village down here for deliverance.
And the man of God has prayed for all of us, including myself.
We thank God, sir. Can you just testify, sir, since you gave your confession last week,
what are the changes you have seen in your life?
Since my confession last week, I have been able to sleep without having nightmares,
eating with dead people or walking with dead people.
It has been a very good experience.
Now I have peace in my heart.
We give glory to God, sir, and we thank Jesus Christ for delivering our father
after he gave his confession here at The SCOAN,
how in the past satan really had used him to deceive and defraud a lot of people.
But today, he is here testifying to the glory of God with his entire family.
We thank Jesus Christ for that.
My name is Martha from Akwa Ibom State and my age is 25 years.
The problem we are facing right now is challenges in our school fees.
It's affecting me because all my mates have gone far.
I completed my SS3 in 2006.
I am just at home doing nothing.
I have been delivered, I thank God.
I believe I am saved, and my dad too has been delivered.
Glory be to God. We thank Jesus Christ for delivering our sister
and also our father here and the entire family.
My name is Defreke Williams. I am from Akwa Ibom State.
The man right beside me is my uncle.
I want to also use this great opportunity to thank The SCOAN and Prophet T.B. Joshua.
In fact, he has been a great blessing to the entire family.
I am very much privileged to be one of those he has singled out and given this great favour.
We the children too had our challenges since we are not actually going on the way it should be.
But by the special grace of God, coming down to The SCOAN,
the man of God prayed for us and laid his hands on us
and right now as I am speaking to you, I feel the change already.
Glory be to God Almighty.
We thank God Almighty for what he has done in the life of this family.
My name is Godswill. I am from Akwa Ibom.
Your age?
I am 10 years old.
Who is the man beside you?
He is my father.
Before coming here, what was the problem you were having?
I used to steal.
Why did you use to steal?
Because satan would be pushing me to go and steal.
The man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for you. How are you feeling now?
I am feeling ok.
I am no longer going to steal again.
Glory be to God. We have heard from the little boy.
He has said that he has been delivered from that spirit that was pushing him to steal
as we listened to the confession of our father here.
My name is Sarah. I am from Akwa Ibom State.
Your age?
I am 16 years old.
We can see a baby in your hands. Who is this baby to you?
It's my baby.
Just tell us, sister, at the age of 16 you are having this baby. What actually led to this?
It was just a mistake and I have learnt from it.
I have learnt that education is the best.
So you mean because of the frustration in the family, that led you to go outside
at your young age and that actually led you to have this child.
Yes.
Now that you have come to the church and Jesus has delivered you,
you are ready to start a new life in Christ?
Yes.
You want to return to school now?
So we listened to the family, just a few members of the family.
We can understand how the spirits that were affecting our father
had also affected the entire family, especially the children.
We have heard it from them that majority of them have been unable to continue their education.
They have been struggling to pay the school fees because the money that was gained
in the past through these illicit activities, as it was received from satan,
also went back to satan and was unable to be used for anything positive
or beneficial in the life of this family.
This is how this young family here has been suffering for many years.
But we give glory to God that deliverance has finally come.
And we here today with a message from Prophet T.B. Joshua.
On behalf of Prophet T.B.Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners,
the man of God said that he wants to support this family so that they can go back to school
in their various educational areas and also to stay close to Jesus Christ,
and continue in the new life they have received by receiving deliverance.
So we here to present to our baba here on behalf of the entire family, the sum of 300 000 Naira
which is a blessing for this family to start a new life in Christ Jesus.
Mr Williams & Family Receives 300,000 Naira
From T.B. Joshua And Emmanuel TV Partners
So once again, this is a sum of 300,000 Naira alongside the Word of God which is The Mirror
as a reminder for this family, to make the Word of God the standard for their lives.
This blessing is a gift so that the children can be assisted back to their schools
and that the family can start a new life now that deliverance has come.
Our father can begin a new clean business in which we know that God Almighty will bless him
to continue the journey and take care of his children.
Sir, what can you say about this blessing?
I thank Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV partners all over the world,
the ushers and all members of this church for taking care of us for the past 1 week we have been here.
May God bless them all.
I never expected something like this.
I thank God.
We believe you are going to use this blessing to take care of your children
and to start a new life and a fresh start.
I am going to use this blessing to start a new life and take care of my children.
I will not go back to a criminal life again.
Thank You, Jesus Christ. We give all the glory to God.
Finally, sir, we would like to ask: What is your advice to our viewers all over the world?
My advice to the viewers all over the world is that they should stay away from crime.
Crime is not a good thing.
Whenever they have a problem, instead of running away from God,
they should run to God. God is there, ready to deliver them.
My name is Esther. I am from Akwa Ibom State.
I am 21 years old.
And who is the man standing beside you?
He is my father.
First and foremost, I am grateful to God Almighty for everything he has done for us.
And I am also very grateful to Prophet T.B. Joshua for his gift to my family.
I am equally grateful to all Emmanuel TV partners all over the world.
Thank you. God bless you all.
Of course, with the money that Prophet T.B. Joshua has given to my father,
I believe he is going to make judicious use of it.
He is going to maybe start a business with it so that he can support the family
and put us through our academics.
I believe all of you have chosen already to follow Jesus Christ and give your life fully to Him.
We are.
Thank You, Jesus Christ. Once again, we thank God for this family.
We pray that God will give everyone here the grace to continue to stay close to Jesus,
make the Word of God the standard for your lives,
and we believe you are all coming back with more wonderful testimonies, in Jesus' name.
Amen.
Thank You, Jesus!
TT: Monica Asefa 01/09/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 24/09/2018